I remember in 2020 when the krona virus
pandemic hit the world and how much fear
was generated worldwide but over the
coming weeks we were able to allow
humanity to come together in a way it
had never come together before artists
were performing online for free
companies were giving away their their
products and services for free and at
cost we were able to organize new ways
of feeding ourselves and entertaining
ourselves and we made sure that every
human being was looked after it started
with people giving away their time and
energy what they had already been
charging for online as they realized
they had the capacity to give it away
for free they started and that had
ripple effects all over the world people
giving away coaching and therapy and
medical information people coming
together and figuring out how to 3d
print face masks and respirators people
come in together and figure you know how
with the overburdens medical system we
can still have as low mortality as
possible we banded together and put a
pause on our financial markets no more
buying and selling of stock or interest
payments no more principal payments we
all just took a breath and everybody was
fed everybody had a roof over their head
and we realized how interconnected we
are how much if one person is fearful
that costs all of us we saw it in the
empty store Shone's in the beginning and
then as things calm down we were able to
figure out systems that didn't mean we
were we were we were all concentrated
into into tiny markets we figured out
grocery delivery systems
and once the pandemic was over we never
went back we had at Cost food delivery
to all of our homes we made sure seniors
were fed and people with with chronic
illnesses were fed we looked after each
other we created it started in all of
these micro ways that that you had to
hear about through that through the
grapevine but eventually the organizers
came on onboard and they started
organizing the groups they started
creating the platforms to be able to
coordinate on a massive level so that
not only were we taking care of each
other during this pandemic but we were
taking care of each other for the next
and the next in the next crisis that we
were knew we were gonna face as a globe
and it stopped being as scary we started
to emotionally support each other going
through this existential crisis of Who
am I now that I can't pay my bills who
am I now that might that I can see I'm
no better than everyone else because my
business failed and does that make me a
failure as a person and those of us who
had already been through that type of
existential crisis because of our own
health challenges and our own financial
circumstances in the previous world were
able to help those who are going through
it for the first time we were able to
step step up and have this topsy-turvy
flipping effect of the poor and the sick
having to take the lead in the world
because they they already had the
infrastructure in place to be able to
help one another they already had the
ability to weather this chaotic storm to
deal with the the isolation and the
loneliness and the boredom and all of
the mental health crisis that came with
it
we I started solution raising as you can
see on on the the the screen it started
out tiny at the very beginning of the
pandemic pandemic in 2020 and now we
have our own platform to be able to
raise solutions all over the world we
were able to figure out how what can we
do right now with a hundred thousand
dollars and ten thousand people and we
in the very beginning ignored the
pandemic because it was everywhere and
we didn't want to focus on that we
focused on
rotation and we focused on community
building and education and healthcare
and what does it look like when we what
can we create from where we are with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars and it grew and grew and people
came on board and we were able to not
only brainstorm amazing potential ideas
they were able to actually implement
them into the world as people sat idle
in their homes overcoming the grief
cycle the need to push it away and not
acknowledge it the anger the fear as
people came out of this they realized
they had all of this time on their hands
and they were able to put that time
towards good use of having generative
conversations coming up with solutions
that are actually possible and those of
us who could afford to put money into
the pool so we could create the
solutions not just for this situation
but for all the situations in the future
and through this pandemic we were able
to see what it looks like for Humanity
to come together to simultaneously lock
down our borders to stop the spread of
the virus and open our hearts to people
all over the world and work together at
a citizen level and not rely on our
governments to come up with solutions we
realized that the distrust we have in
our media and our governments cost us
all as we it was very hard to
distinguish between truth and and
untruth it was even when it was truthful
and things were being done in the for
the benefit of all conspiracy theories
abound to people who were scared to face
the possible financial implications were
still out partying and still spreading
spreading the virus and then we had the
global learning of what that cost us and
we had to come up with a way to truly
allow everybody to understand the truth
of every issue what is so we developed
systems that were where we were able to
understand what is the what is the virus
how has it spread what is the best
information right now if you have it
what do you do and we were also able so
to create the Lehman's in
so that we could have the best source of
information that we could trust that
wasn't coming necessarily from our
individual governments or from the media
but from our best estimate of science
and the scientists were able to tell us
that information and we created parallel
systems for scientists and experts to
come together and create solutions so
that the vaccine was fast-tracked and we
were able to to save more lives more
easily we were able to come together and
crowdsource respirators that every time
there was a shortage in the medical
supply chain we were able to crowdsource
3d print come up with ways to innovate
we were able to figure out how to
entertain ourselves we started having
all of these online meetings for book
clubs and my kids started having play
dates online and having conversations
with people who were just a few blocks
away or provinces and countries away we
were able to come together in a way that
we had never come before together as a
planet and at the end we refused to go
back to how it was before